# ANDREW SCHNIEDER FRONT-END/FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

# **Summary**

I love the internet! Being able to build sites and apps that people enjoy using, and find valuable has been a dream come true. I primarily focus on clean, simple application interface, as well as full stack development. My varied work history has allowed me to proudly bring team building skills, organizational knowledge, and management experience to projects I've had the opportunity to be a part of.

# **Employment**

# **Andytown Coffee Roasters**

San Francisco

Porter Nov 2013 to Oct 2014

Andytown Coffee Roasters began construction in the fall of 2013. I assisted the owners with the remodeling, and later became their first employee. I continued to work there for the year and supported the establishment in multiple roles.

#### **Telltale Games**

**Format Quality Assurance Tester** 

Mar 2013 to Sep 2013

Telltale Games is an award winning game studio in San Rafael, CA. As a tester, my duty was to process outbound submissions to Playstation and correct any discrepancies with Playstation's formatting standards.

## **Sony Playstation**

**Format Quality Assurance Tester** 

Mar 2012 to Mar 2013

Sony Playstation has strict standards for any video game title that is submitted for use on the Playstation consoles. The duties of a Format QA Tester were to test submitted titles for failures to comply with Sony's submission standards.

#### The Base Studio

Rotoscope Artist Feb 2011 to Nov 2011

The Base Studio is a Visual Effects studio in Foster City, CA. During my employment there, I digitally rotoscoped 2Dimensional movie frames to be used for 3Dimensional movie display. Films I have worked on include Captain America The First Avenger, Hansel and Gretel Witch Hunters, Tornado Alley, Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows Part 7, and other smaller projects.

#### **Delta Airlines**

Cincinnati, Northern Kentucky International Airport

**Customer Service Supervisor** 

May 2000 to May 2007

My job duties as a supervisor included taxiing aircraft, guiding aircraft into and out of gates, supervision of 20+ employees per shift, refueling aircraft, handling passenger complaints, maintaining communication between departments, and supervision of aircraft loading.

# **Projects**

#### **Trading Faces**

Trading Faces is a playful, functional game that utilizes a facial recognition api to compare players<sup>9</sup> faces. Built with Ruby on Rails api, Javascript, Ruby, Handlebars, and Bootstrap. I was part of a team that developed this app, and we presented it for our final project at Dev Bootcamp.

#### PoupTube

PoupTube is a video web application that only finds videos on youtube with less than 400 views. Built using Sinatra, Ruby, jQuery, and AJAX.

### **Contact**

**EMAIL:** andrewschnieder@gmail.com

WEBSITE: Aschnied.github.io PHONE: 573.644.4684 LOCATION: San Francisco LINKEDIN: andrewjohnschnieder

**GITHUB:** Aschnied

# Education

### **Dev Bootcamp**

Dev Bootcamp is a short-term, immersive program that turns aspiring beginners into full stack web developers. Graduates are capable of using Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL (SQLite and PostgreSQL), Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, ActiveRecord, jQuery, AJAX, and RSpec.

# **Academy of Art University**

Video Game Design - 2009 to 2011

## **University of Cincinati**

BS Biology 2003

Majored in Biology and Pre-Veterinary Medicine

# **Skills**

#### **WEB DEVELOPMENT**

Ruby

**Javascript** 

HTML/CSS

iQuery

AJAX

SOL

ActiveRecord

Sinatra

Git

**Ruby on Rails** 

Handlebars

**Bootstrap** 

**RSpec** 

#### INTERPERSONAL/ORGANIZATIONAL

**Team Building** 

Time Management

**Employee Management** 

**Customer Service** 

**Organizational Techniques**